Contact

+62 8515 6960 832 (Work) bariqalmukasyah@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ bariqalmukasyah (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Network Engineering Customer Support Technical Support

Certifications

Network Technician Career Path CCNA: Introduction to Networks British Council Core Skill Test Junior Cybersecurity Analyst Career Path

Muhammad Bariq Al Mukasyah

IT Support

Semarang, Central Java, Indonesia

Summary

I am an IT Support Specialist with more than 5 years of experience, committed to providing reliable technical support and effective solutions. I am dedicated to ensuring systems and devices run smoothly, as well as assisting end-users in overcoming technical challenges. In my professional journey, I've had the opportunity to work with diverse teams and tackle complex technical issues, all while enhancing network efficiency, and hardware and software problem-solving. My core skills include rapid troubleshooting, network configuration, and a strong customer service focus, all underpinned by integrity, perseverance, and a thirst for knowledge. I believe that these qualities are vital for success in the IT Support field, and I'm always eager to expand my IT knowledge to continue delivering top-tier support to organizations. If you are seeking someone dedicated to helping you achieve tech success, let's connect!

Experience

Bromindo

IT Support Technician

August 2021 - Present (3 years 4 months)

Semarang, Central Java, Indonesia

- Responsible for the entire internet network at the head office and branch offices
- Responsible for the entire work support devices such as smartphones and laptops
- Ensure that all CCTV and office telephones are working properly
- Ensure local servers are working properly

PT MEDIA SARANA DATA (GMEDIA)

Access Support

November 2019 - July 2021 (1 year 9 months)

Semarang, Central Java, Indonesia

- Setup, Troubleshoot, and Maintenance Customer's link quality and local connection on site
- Survey and Installation customer's connection. *Wireless (Radio) and Wired (Fiber Optic)
- Using MikroTik and Ubiquity Wireless
- Using monitoring tools (The Dude and Cacti)
- Create Report (Daily)

PadiNET

Technical Support Engineer
July 2018 - November 2019 (1 year 5 months)

Bali Province, Indonesia

- Setup, Troubleshoot, and Maintenance Customer's link quality and local connection on site
- Survey and Installation customer's connection. *Wireless (Radio)
- As 1st level Customer Support (Call/WhatsApp/Email). Solving customer problem by remote
- Using MikroTik and Ubiquity Wireless
- Using monitoring tools (The Dude and Cacti)
- Create Report (Monthly)

Sofitel Bali Nusa Dua Beach Resort

IT Engineer on Site

July 2018 - November 2019 (1 year 5 months)

Bali, Indonesia

- As "IT Support" to handling Hotel Staff Problem (Hardware, Software, Connection)
- As 1st level to handle Hotel Guest Internet connection problem
- Maintenance, and Troubleshooting Access Point (Cisco Aironet)
- Monitoring and Maintenance Hotel Billing for Premium Wi-Fi connection
- Create Daily and Maintenance Report

PadiNET

Technical Support Engineer May 2017 - January 2018 (9 months)

Bali Province, Indonesia

Education

Universitas Stikubank Semarang

Bachelor's of Informatics Engineering, Information Technology · (September 2020 - October 2024)

SMK Negeri 7 Semarang Computer and Network Engineering · (2014 - 2018)